Hello Friends I am Mahesh from TrekBook India
Todays topic is Top 5 Two-Wheeler insurance companies in India
so before we begin, let's see
criteria's that I have considered to select best insurance
first & foremost criteria is
How strong is cashless garages network of insurance company
this is very important since maximum 2-wheelers are there in India
& in case of accident, network garage is must for repairs
and to get cashless insurance without any hassle
just submit the bike for repairs & you get it back without paying any cash
so this important point I have considered
second is Which add-on rider options are given by company
as an example - Zero Depreciation
in case Plastic part brakes & you don't have taken Zero Dep
then you get only 50% cost of broken part
so I will prefer to get Zero Dep cover by the company
then accessories gets covered
medical cover, passenger cover is there
like in accident case driver & passenger hospitalization expenses
this can be also covered by insurance company as additional option
so you should look at this option too
Third point is How is the Customer Care Support?
you need to see if they have 24x7 attention line
because anything can happen anytime & getting timely help is important
and main point again - coming to the Claim Settlement Ratio
IRDA - Insurance Development Authority of India
IRDA publishes data of claim settlement ratios by insurance companies
so now I am moving on to the chart
so I have taken an example at the top of chart
my friends 2Wh Vespa VXL125 Std model, 125cc
this is December 2016 model
for this I took out online quotations
this is just a sample
our main focus is not on example
focus will be on which company is best based on criteria's which I told you
so first column is Insurance company name
second column belongs to claim settlement ratio in the year 2019-20
this is IRDA data
this I have taken from insurance dekho dot com website
so indexing of table is done on that key
means company having highest claim settlement ratio tops the list
company  having lowest claim settlement ratio is at bottom of table
chart have become slightly bigger, but t this time I have included each company
during my last car insurance video I skipped some companies & people asked questions!
now see that third party cover highlighted in blue colour
so that is common across all
because the third party insurance price is fixed price
so 752 Rs in this case is constant for all companies
previous column is IDV Insured Declared Value
means How much amount you will get if your bike gets 100% damage
this is flexible & you can increase it, but then premium will go up accordingly
third column is Zero Depreciation cover
if you wish, you can take that
it will add to some charges
& then road toe assistance
so personally as per me Zero Dep & Road toe assistance is better to take
so if you take both these riders
so rider will have added cost depending on company to company
& finally it comes out to Total Package Premium
over & above you have 18% GST
so second last column will have amount to be paid
last column shows the network garages
so how many network garages a company have?
so considering all these I have numbered top companies
& why that I want to tell you
so I have given number 1 for SBI General insurance
there are 2 reasons for that
one is their Claim settlement ration is 90%
second they have highest 16K+ network garages
so compared to other companies SBI Gen have both claim settlement ratio & network garages good
that is the reason I have sleeted them at Number 1
Number 2 is HDFC General Ergo Insurance
their Claim settlement ratio is 91.23%
and
they have @6800+ network garages
for this reason I have kept them at Number 2
Number 3 is Tata AIG General insurance
TATA AIG is also one of the well known insurance company in India
so their claim settlement ratio is also 90.49%
& they have 5000+ network garages
so they rank on third number as per me
fourth number is Tokyo General insurance
their claim settlement ration is highest 95.3%
but their network garages are 4300+
that is why I have kept them on fourth ranking
fifth ranking is Royal Sundaram General Insurance
their claim settlement ration is second highest i.e. 92.66%
their network garages are also 4600+
now why I have shuffled Tokyo & Royal sundaram?
because I liked the road assistance & Zero dep coverage in Tokoy Gen
that is why I have kept them on fourth ranking
I have highlighted separately ...
those companies having higher network garages like
Chola mangalam gen insurance have 7100+ garages
& ICICI Lombard have 5600+
& Bharti Axa General have 5200+
that is why I have highlighted them too
so those having 5000+
such companies I have highlighted
but Top 5 I have already told you
so again while selecting insurance do select riders
as per the company in top 5 giving you lowest premium, you can go ahead
so thank you very much
do tell me in comments if you liked the video
bye for now